[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the fourth episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
This time with a conditional branch.
Eventually, we'll be able to do something like what you're seeing now.
It's divided into four sections, and each section has a different color and
I'd like to make something that is subject to expansion and contraction.
Well, this time we're going to do it.
First, a conditional branch using an if statement
Then a conditional branch using the step and mix functions
At the end, each of those branches is a color or
Scaling and different processing.
So let's get to it.
This is the GLSL TOP we will be working on.
It's almost identical to the default one.
This is how the texture is already loaded
We did it last time, but we put a value of uv in the value of p.
So I'd like to start with an if statement
if
In this case, I'd like to separate the x-coordinate locations.
first (of all)
I'll write it down.
When x is less than or equal to 0.5, this is what you do.
I've written code to do something else at other times
If you make a split.
We're going to put a different color in here for each of them.
This time, sir.
First of all, declare vec4 color above, and then use
Each of these colors.
I'm going to put it in this if statement
Now... when it's less than this 0.5 and when it's not.
It's the same one in there.
For example, bgra for rgba.
Let me put it this way.
If you do this, the color of the image changes at -0.5.
I can make these things.
Right now, we're using 0.5 as our threshold, but if we make it smaller, we're going to be able to make it smaller.
The threshold takes over and goes to the left.
That's a 0.2 location.
If you do 0.8 or something like that, they'll come this way.
I'd like to set it back to 0.5.
I can do conditional branching with GLSL with no problem with this.
Probably doing a lot of research on GLSL.
An if statement is a slower process than an
I think you'll see a lot of people saying it's better not to use it.
You can write like this when you do.
I'm sure there will be a lot of things that come out of this.
I'd like to introduce you to one of the ways to write it.
I'm going to copy this.
I'd like to write another piece of code over here.
For the sake of the code we're about to write.
This color that is vec4.
I'd like to use it as a vec3.
Leave one comment out of this area.
I got an error.
vec4(color, 1.0)
I want to keep the alpha fixed.
I'll make it this way.
The first way to do this conditional branch is to use the step function
This is called the OpenGL quick reference card, and it's a
It's what's called a cheat sheet or something like that.
I'll leave this link in the summary section later, too.
You can see how to use it here
It's a step function, so you have to find the step.
It's right around here.
It's very small, so I'm going to make it bigger.
This one.
In the setp function, if you take the argument edge and x, you can use
So if x is less than edge, it returns 0.
In the opposite case, if you return 1, you can use it like this
I'd like to try to write some code with it.
TouchDesigner and this one.
For example, if the float edge is 0.5 and
If float x is p.x and
When this is happening.
The result.
step(edge, p.x) and
It goes like this.
For example
I'd like to visualize this result a bit.
First of all, if you put this result in vec3
It goes something like this.
I think you'll see what I mean when you see this.
The value of x in p is less than 0.5
So the left half is zero.
That means the right half has a value of 1 in it.
If we express this in an if statement, the left side is false and
The right side is true.
Here's one for starters.
Step function.
I'll also use the mix function
You know, I'd come back here again... and I'd have to do a search.
Here's how to use it.
The mix takes the values x and y and a
In this case, from this x, the value of y is transitioned by a
It's called linear interpolation.
For example, if this x is 0, then y is 100
Suppose that the value
When a moves from 0 to 1.
This is where we're moving from 0 to 100.
So, for example, if you put 0.5 in a, you'll get
When the number 50 comes back.
It's like this.
I'd like to write a little bit of this code
0 of a mix, 1
That's what happened a few minutes ago.
This kind of thing.
What I want to do this time is
mix On the left.
We'll put in this texture.
Texture p
When the vec3 rgb color
If you don't, you'll get a vec4 back.
rgb Put this in.
Another one, this time with a different color as gbr.
You can put it in here.
I was putting 0s and 1s in there for now.
Put rgb on the left side and gbr on the right
in this way
Oh, you're getting an error.
What's funny?
fragColor No shin color here.
This is already vec3, so I don't need this one.
This is how you do it.
Oh, you're getting the error again.
I need this in here.
It's like this. It's like this.
They're split down the middle.
The colors are a little different, the code is a little different.
bgr
It's a gbr, so bgr
Like this.
This way, you'll get exactly the same thing as above.
Since this step function returns 0 or 1, the
The 0s and 1s come back with a crisp split.
This is where the conditional branch with an if statement and
I would like to compare the conditional branching of the step and the mix
Since this still hasn't been cooked
Just put some absTime or something in here.
It's moving like it's cooking.
I'd like to compare them as they are cooked
If you use an if statement, it's usually 190
It was around 200.
If you don't use if statements, here's a
I mean, around 110.
Right here.
Now you can see that the process is faster using this step and mix.
I think that's clear.
Also, the step function is...
I used a float just a few minutes ago.
You can also take a vector value
I'd like to give it a shot.
I'm going to set this edge to vec3.
For example... 0.2, 0.5, 0.6
And put in.
Here's how to write this.
When comparing this edge and x, the x is also
He said he'd have to go to vec3.
I'll try to take the same mold.
So, as a vec3
If you include this p.x.
It goes like this.
I'm getting a few errors.
Don't worry about it for now
You don't have to put it in here.
I didn't want to have to put it in.
This is where x, not p.x
Right here.
It goes like this.
It's a little hard to see, so here you go.
I'd like to change that.
RGB
Just to be clear.
Zero. This is a zero and this is a one.
I'll put these numbers in.
So this is what it looks like.
Black on the left and white on the right.
Let's change this one up a bit.
Let's call it WHITE with BLACK.
I think it's easy to understand.
BLACK WHITE
Depending on this value, the
It's a form of transition from black to white.
Earlier, there was only one of these junctions.
This time, there are three forks in the road.
It's divided like this
We'll see how it actually works.
I'd like to write a little bit about it.
I don't need this, so turn it off.
That's a start.
It's this p.x.
If x is less than 0.2, in this case
It's like this.
First of all, this vec3(0., 0., 0.)
You're going in here.
If x is less than 0.2
What does this mean?
This p.x value is compared to this 0.2, 0.5, and 0.6
compared to this 0.2, 0.5, and 0.6 respectively.
Since the result p.x is smaller than the result
This is what it looks like when the zeroes go in.
There's a zero in there.
Now.
If x is greater than 0.2 and
If x is less than 0.5, you get this value
In this case, since p.x is greater than 0.2
There's a one in here.
If you do this, you'll see red like this
this means that
And now between 0.5 and 0.6.
Between here and here.
This color is greater than 0.2 and less than 0.6, which is greater than 0.5
therefore
1, 1, 0 and
It goes like this.
Lastly, if the value is greater than 0.6
Everything is bigger than this 0.2.
It's bigger than 0.5 and bigger than 0.6.
This is one and
It goes like this.
Black, red, yellow and white.
This is the kind of thing that comes up.
I'm going to comment out on this like this
It's like this.
If you change these numbers.
Sometimes they're a little off.
With an if sentence, I'd have to write four more of these.
But in this case, it's just this one line
Since we only need one line, or rather this edge calculation and this one line
I'm sure it will be very refreshing.
And the process is light.
Benefits.
That's what I was saying, but...
At first glance, I think it's a little hard to get to know.
Of course, the more if-sentences you have, the more
I'm sure there's going to be a difference in performance.
If you're doing it and it doesn't affect your performance that much, then
I'm more of an if statement.
It's easy to understand, and it's not a bad idea.
Personally, I think it is.
therefore
This time, sir.
The rest of the sample goes back to the if portion of the sample.
I'd like to continue working on it.
But, of course, those who can do well in this step and mix will be able to
Please keep trying!
So, let's go back to the GLSL on which this if statement is written
This one.
It's like this.
The first thing to find out.
We're only at the junction of x at the moment.
I'm going to add the y-coordinate junction point to this as well.
What we do.
The uniform variable vec2
I included a vec2 variable called uThreshold
I'd like to use just x here for now.
This is how you do it.
I can make a branch of x, though.
Since this is out here.
Press Load Uniform Names to get in.
Well, I'm glad you're in.
We don't need this time, so turn it off.
0.50.
In vec2, I'd use these first two.
If this x is in now as 0.5
So you can change the numbers here and it works like this.
We're on the move.
I'll set it to 0.5 now for now.
If you do 0.5 for y as well
We can create a split in the middle standard
I'd like to put them in one by one.
I'm going to write a branch here.
First, p.x is less than uThreshold.x
That is, less than 0.5.
And now, if p.y is less than uThreshold.y and
I'll put these in.
Now.
else if
If p.x is greater than uThreshold.x and
If p.x is less than uThreshold.y
I'll put in a
And now, if x is small and
uThreshold.y is over here.
If x is less than 0.5 and uThreshold.x is less than x, and
There is a case where y is greater than uThreshold.y
Now, there are three conditions.
And the rest of it is just that...
When p.x is greater than uThreshold.x and
When p.y is greater than uThreshold.y and
That's what goes into this ELSE.
I'm going to change this color a little bit from here.
I was fine with rgba at first.
I don't care what it is, but rbga or whatever.
There's a little bit of a color change here, too.
One more.
Like gbra.
You're with us.
rbga
I think it's going to be a color-changing experience.
So there are four different patterns.
Of course, if you move the value here.
It's going to be one of those things where the center changes.
I'd like to make this work a little bit more dynamically.
Make it big once.
LFO
and Noise
Put a Hold in.
If you make this a Pulse
So it's now.
Every second.
I'm going to get a random value that's in here.
I've created a
This and Math.
Once before.
We should name this value.
You name it.
threshold[X, Y]
I've named it.
It's like this.
As a value of -1 to 1 comes in.
For example, let's put in 0.2 to 0.8.
Put a Null in here.
Put this value into uThreshold
this means that
Like this.
This will change this place every second.
You can create something called
As it is.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Put a Filter CHOP in here and then add
I tried to make the animation smooth.
Let's make some space for you.
Here.
It was here last time.
I'm going to add the ability to zoom in and out.
I'm going to show you one little bit of code
At this p.
I'll make sure to include a uRepeat
There are four here, so let's do it with vec4
The first one is uRepeat.x
This is the second one. uRepeat.y
The third one is uRepeat.z and the fourth one is called xyz.
and the fourth one is called xyz
I'm getting another WARNING here.
Load Uniform
When you do Names, this is automatically entered into the
Now the number that goes in here.
I'd like to include it.
I made the same thing and now
repeat
I don't care what it is, but REPEAT[X, Y, Z, W]
I put in a
Again, from -1.
Let's keep it at about 1 to 3 for now.
I put a number on it.
I'd like to use this Null reference again.
Put a Merge CHOP in here once.
I'll tie this together.
So now threshold xy and repeat xyz.
It's a form of entry.
Like this repeatX.
I'm going to take all of this here.
x y z w and
I can do this.
It's still not quite as smooth as I thought it would be.
I'd like to put a filter in here as well.
in this way
I think it now looks like the first sample I showed you.
It's right here in the middle.
Maybe you could make it a mouse action, for example.
various
In short, if you come in with a CHOP, you can come in with anything you want.
I think it could be interesting to use.
This one is showing all the same images now.
Even if you put out slightly different images in pieces.
I thought it would be interesting.
Let's display it.
Like this.
It might be a little different from the first one, but
It went like this.
Well, that's enough for now.
In addition to the YouTube tutorials on TDSW
We offer live streaming workshops about two weekends a month.
If you are interested in TDSW through the tutorial
Please come and visit us at our live streaming workshops!
Also, TDSW uses Patreon
Currently, the Tutorial Creation Support Plan
Workshop Video Plan
Workshop Video and Live Streaming Plan
There are three plans available
It is more profitable than attending the workshop by itself.
I hope you will consider it.
Please check out each link in the overview section!
Thank you for watching.
Please subscribe to the channel if you'd like.
goodbye
[Music]